Brendan Jones

I am a Front-End Web Developer with a passion for web design and creativity. I am always on the lookout for opportunities to test my skills and bring my experience into a team based environment.

(270)-289-1170 Email - Portfolio Github - LinkedIn

SKILLS

CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, React JS, Styled Components, Express JS, Node JS, SASS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Rest APIs, C#, Version Control

PROJECTS

Marketplace - Direct Software Solutions - Website

- Work-in-progress React Js e-commerce site built using Styled Components, Node J's, Express JS, Stripe, and MongoDB.
- Custom coded JSX and Styled Components/CSS.
- Built in custom functionality using props and destructuring.

Carbonhouse — Code: Website

- Fully mobile responsive landing page designed using Figma
- Customly coded using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and SASS

Crypto Axios Request — Code: Website

- Built from scratch React Js cryptocurrency table using the Axios package with Node JS to request data from a REST API
- Styled using Tailwind CSS,
- Request and display data using hooks, mapping, and filter.

Nikola Tesla Tribute Page — Code: Website

- Responsive landing page built with Bootstrap
- Customly coded and styled using HTML5 and CSS

Weather Forecast — Code: Website

- Built and coded using custom HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Uses async/await fetch to request data from a REST API
- Uses classes and DOM manipulation to help display data

EXPERIENCE

Direct Software Solutions — Apprenticeship

November 2022 - Present

I am helping design, create, and implement functionality into the marketplace for the parent site.

MTD, Martin TN — Assembler

August 2021 - March 2022

Inspected lawn mower frames for safety and quality.

Rotech, Murray KY – Warehouse

April 2020 - March 2021

Filled ticket orders and kept in stock inventory.

EDUCATION

West Kentucky Community and Technical College, Paducah KY — A.S.

2022

Key Courses:

- C# I and C# II
- Java I and Java II
- Web Design and JavaScript
- Relational Databases